<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
      <author email="bayard@generationjava.com">Henri Yandell</author>
      <title>Simple-JNDI</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="The Problem">
<p>
Simple-JNDI is intended to solve two problems. The first is that of finding a container independent way of opening a database connection, the second is to find a good way of specifying application configurations.
</p>
<p>
In a J2EE container, you can use JNDI as a javax.sql.DataSource factory. This code however is not usable outside of a J2EE container as you cannot guarrentee you have a JNDI implementation available, and to be honest, you don't want to start some other server to make your simple script run. Simple-JNDI is not a server, it is merely an API, however it looks exactly the same as the JNDI client code used in a J2EE container.
</p>
<p>
Applications need configuration. A servlets container uses the web.xml files to configure, while a J2EE container uses a different system, for example, JBoss has a jboss.jcml configuration file which sets a system up via JMX managed beans. An application <i>could</i> however use Simple-JNDI for parameter values.
</p>
</section>
    <section name="A Solution">
    <p>A simple implementation of JNDI. It is entirely library based, so no server instances are started, and it sits upon Java .properties files, XML files or Windows-style .ini files, so it is easy to use and simple to understand. The files may be either on the file system or in the classpath. </p>
    <p>Simple-JNDI no longer depends on external jars for its basic functionality, however to get certain optional features you will still need to download external jars. This is discussed on the <a href="Optional.html">optional features</a> page. </p>
</section>
<section name="Getting more help">
    <p>Feel free to ask any questions to the user's <a href="http://www.osjava.org/simple-jndi/mail-lists.html">mailing list</a>. Please report bugs either in the <a href="http://www.osjava.org:8080/jira/secure/BrowseProject.jspa?id=10000 ">issue tracker</a> or to the <a href="http://www.osjava.org/simple-jndi/mail-lists.html">mailing list</a>. </p>
    </section>
</body>
</document>
