<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
      <author email="bayard@generationjava.com">Henri Yandell</author>
      <title>Optional Features</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
<section name="Optional Features">
<p>In addition to the basic features of Simple-JNDI, there are four features that are an option to use and may require extra dependencies. </p>
</section>
<section name="INI files">
<p>Simple-JNDI is chiefly based on .properties files, but it can also understand simple .ini files if such is your preference. This feature is enabled by just having a file ending with .ini available, though a .properties and .xml file take precedence. <p>
</section>
<section name="XML files">
<p>Simple-JNDI can also understand XML files, though you will need the xml-parser jar available from the <a href="Download.html">Download</a> page. Sitting between .properties and .ini files in terms of precedence, XML files are enabled by having a file end with .xml and having the jar in the classpath. Remember, a legal XML file has only one root tag. <p>
</section>
<section name="Type converting>
<p>You don't have to just deal in Strings. Simple-JNDI can automatically convert the values to the Object of your choice via the Jakarta Commons Convert library. Make sure you have the commons-convert jar, see <a href="Download.html">Download</a> page, in your classpath and set a sub-parameter of 'type' in your properties file. For example, person.age.type=java.lang.Integer will make person.age an Integer object. </p>
<p>Although the DataSource system appears to use this, it merely mimics it and you will not need to include the commons-convert jar in your classpath. </p>
</section>
<section name="Connection pooling">
<p>Often when using a DataSource you will want to pool the Connections the DataSource is handing out. Simple-JNDI delegates to the Jakarta Commons DBCP project for this feature so you will need commons-dbcp, commons-pool and commons-collections jars in your classpath. Again, the <a href="Download.html">Download</a> page provides links to the jars. </p>
<p>The feature is turned on by adding a sub-parameter of 'pool=true' in your datasource properties file. For example, ApacheDS.pool=true, will turn DBCP Connection pooling on for the ApacheDS datasource. </p>
</section>
</body>
</document>
