<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
      <author email="bayard@generationjava.com">Henri Yandell</author>
      <title>Task List</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Tasks">
<ul>
<li>Types. com.foo.Value can have a partner key of com.foo.Value.type which specifies the type of object to use for the key. </li>
<li>Implement Type in such a way that the object to create may be specified, say JDOPersistenceFactory, and that sub-properties may be set as bean properties.</li>
<li>Implement binding so that values may be stored in the system, making it Read/Write. </li>
<li>Implementing the list methods so you can see the values in a particular directory/properties file. </li>
<li>Searches. Consider implementing DirContext. </li>
<li>Switch to using Names in the system, with the String argument being turned to a Name based on delimiters specified in the jndi.properties. Allow more than one delimiter.</li>
<li>Other DataSource like things? JDO?</li>
<li>XML underneath as well as .properties</li>
<li>If root is unspecified, then use the classpath: <b>DONE v0.3</b></li>
<li>Allow the root to be a classpath root, ie) com.generationjava: <b>DONE v0.3</b></li>
<li>Allow the root to be a url, so properties can be found online</li>
<li>Hook up DBCP or some other connection pool.</li>
<li>Make it nice to hook up Enhanced drivers from DbUtils??</li>
<li>Use OrderedProperties to order the underlying .properties files. </li>
<li>Allow the delimiter in the search values to be configurable, so people can more easily mimic LDAP etc: <b>DONE v0.3</b></li>
<li>Test if ProductionDS.com.generationjava.jndi.datasource is obtainable [from examples page]</li>
<li>Confirm that jars and zips may be used in the classpath protocol. </li>
<li>Add multiple-line format for .properties files. ie) if there are equal keys, they should create a collection. Note, with the OrderedProperties this becomes a list and not a collection. </li>
<li>Add a jdbc implementation underneath for the configuration. </li>
</ul>

</section>
</body>
</document>
