<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="bayard@generationjava.com">Henri Yandell</author>
    <title>Scheduling scrapes</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
  <section name="Scheduling scrapes"><p>
Scheduling is the art of deciding when to run your scraper. There are two schedulers available by default

<pre>
SimpleScheduler
QuartzScheduler
</pre>

</p></section><section name="SimpleScheduler"><p>

The best way to describe this scheduler is as the 'run it now' scheduler. When you run the OSCube Engine, it will immediately run the scraper once, and never again.

<pre>
Xxx.scheduler=Simple
</pre>

SimpleScheduler is the default option so does not need to be explicitly specified, and is most commonly used when an external cron-job is used, or for testing.

(TODO: There will be a testing mode for OSCube at a later date)

</p></section><section name="QuartzScheduler"><p>

This allows you to specify when you'd like the scraper to run using the de-facto standard of the UNIX cron system, only on startup (as with the <code>SimpleScheduler</code>), or on a repeating basis.

</p></section><section name="startup"><p>

<pre>
Xxx.scheduler=Quartz
Xxx.schedule=startup
</pre>

</p></section><section name="repeating"><p>

<pre>
Xxx.scheduler=Quartz
Xxx.schedule=simple
Xxx.schedule.interval=&lt;integer milliseconds&gt;
Xxx.schedule.repeat=&lt;integer number of times to repeat&gt;
</pre>

Confusingly the schedule in this case is called <code>simple</code>. The <code>interval</code> is the number of milliseconds to separate each scrape with, and the optional <code>repeat</code> is the number of times to perform the scrape. If unspecified it will go forever.

</p></section><section name="cron"><p>

<pre>
Xxx.scheduler=Quartz
Xxx.schedule=cron
Xxx.schedule.cron=&lt;cron string&gt;
</pre>

Quartz's implementation of the UNIX Cron system, their documentation <a href="httphttp://www.opensymphony.com/quartz/tutorial.html#cronTriggers">http://www.opensymphony.com/quartz/tutorial.html#cronTriggers</a> is probably the best place to read up on it.

Scraping every 5 minutes would be:

<pre>
Xxx.scheduler=Quartz
Xxx.schedule=cron
Xxx.schedule.cron=0 0/5 * * * ?
</pre>

NOTE: Quartz adds a column to the front of the classic cron text to represent seconds, the above example would have only been <code>0/5 * * * ?</code> in the usual cron syntax.
  </p></section>
  </body>

</document>
