<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
      <author email="bayard@generationjava.com">Henri Yandell</author>
      <title>Task List</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Tasks">
<ul>
<li>Allow the delimiter in the search values to be configurable, so people can more easily mimic LDAP etc: <b>DONE v0.3</b></li>
<li>If root is unspecified, then use the classpath: <b>DONE v0.3</b></li>
<li>Allow the root to be a classpath root, ie) org.osjava: <b>DONE v0.3</b></li>
<li><b>-0.3 released-</b></li>
<li>Use OrderedProperties to order the underlying .properties files. <b>DONE v0.4</b></li>
<li>Types. com.foo.Value can have a partner key of com.foo.Value.type which specifies the type of object to use for the key. <b>DONE v0.4</b></li>
<li>Add multiple-line format for .properties files. ie) if there are equal keys, they should create a collection. Note, with the OrderedProperties this becomes a list and not a collection. <b>DONE v0.4</b></li>
<li>XML underneath as well as .properties: <b>DONE v0.4</b></li>
<li><b>-0.4 released-</b></li>
<li>Allow converters to be configured/plugged in somehow. Add new converters. [<b>URL/Boolean converters added in v0.5</b>] </li>
<li>Allow users to bind their own variables on top of the properties. <b>DONE v0.5</b>. This would only be for a single instance of the context, though the factory could return the same instance every time. </li>
<li>Place the System properties before the simple-jndi layer so that -D may override it. <b>DONE v0.5</b>.</li>
<li><b>-0.5 released-</b></li>
<li>Simple-JNDI parameters may now be read through simple-jndi. <b>DONE v0.6</b></li>
<li>Test if ProductionDS.org.osjava.jndi.datasource is obtainable [from examples page] <b>DONE. v0.6</b>: Confirmed</li>
<li>Handle java:/ on a Windows platform. Filenames are unable to contain colons. <b>DONE. v0.6</b>: java: resolves to java on all platforms </li>
<li>Write maven.xml to do the test-config copy to target/test-classes. <b>DONE. v0.6</b>: Changed project.xml to handle this. </li>
<li><b>-0.6 release??-</b></li>
<li>Put the standard configuration options into the JNDI scope itself and pay attention for when they are changed. Thus allowing the system to change at runtime. </li>
<li>Implement Type in such a way that the object to create may be specified, say JDOPersistenceFactory, and that sub-properties may be set as bean properties.</li>
<li>Implement binding so that values may be stored in the system, making it Read/Write. </li>
<li>Implementing the list methods so you can see the values in a particular directory/properties file. </li>
<li>Searches. Consider implementing DirContext. </li>
<li>Switch to using Names in the system, with the String argument being turned to a Name based on delimiters specified in the jndi.properties. Allow more than one delimiter.</li>
<li>Other DataSource like things? JDO?</li>
<li>Allow the root to be a url, so properties can be found online</li>
<li>Hook up DBCP or some other connection pool.</li>
<li>Make it nice to hook up Enhanced drivers from DbUtils??</li>
<li>Confirm that jars and zips may be used in the classpath protocol. </li>
<li>Add a jdbc implementation underneath for the configuration. </li>
<li>Allow the underlying Properties class to use [when applicable] to be specified. </li>
<li>multiple domains. ie) Configure org.osjava to use .properties over http, and org.osjava to use xml over classpath. </li>
<li>Implement a Name class which finds the lookup key separator and injects that inside the name values [a string array]</li>
<li>When a value is unbound, don't return to the default but instead make it so it throws an exception when you try to obtain that value [unless bound again]. </li>
<li>Allow a map-delimiter so that something like  bob.foo.thing#bah=fred uses bah as the key, and fred as the value. </li>
<li>Is there a way to specify the type of a List or Map, or must ArrayList and HashMap always be used?</li>
<li>Create a Config class. Base it on previous written ones. Allow it to have a context stack, basic conversion methods and a root context concept [starts with a '.', or whatever that value is].</li>
<li>Write a simple-jndi server/client setup. Maybe use beep4j</li>
<li>Enable BlahDS.url so you can see the url of a datasource. Block passwords. </li>
<li>Implement DataSource creation as a part of the converter. </li>
<li>Test DataSources in various situations. Given a lookup of java:/TestDS and a delimiter of /, a directory of java: and a file of TestDS.properties, it appears to still look for TestDS/url and not url. Basically the PropertiesDataSource is buggy in its lookup. </li>
<li>Static back end to the binding, so that different contexts can share values. </li>
<li>Provide a .ini back-end support. </li>
<li>Implement satisfactory unit testing. </li>
</ul>

</section>
</body>
</document>
